## **Thomas Chiang**

Home address: 10 Widcombe Hill, Bath BA2 6EB, UK

Mobile: +44(0)784-580-7909

Email: tomchiang30115@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/thomas-chiang-3aa175180/

## Personal profile

I describe myself as an honest, reliable and determined individual who uses many different approaches to complete any given task. I can adapt to new environments and always thirst for more knowledge. As a graduate with many different experiences in many fields, I can say I am ready to take on any given challenge.

## **Education**

University of Bath Oct 2021 – Nov 2022

Degree: MSc Data Science (TBA)

In this course, I was able to understand the principles of machine learning, data pre-processing, data training and modelling, as well as the regulations and legislations behind data science. I am experienced in programming languages such as Python, SQL, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, as well as libraries such as pandas, sci-kit learn, TensorFlow and PyTorch for machine learning and training models.

Heriot-Watt University Sep 2016 – Oct 2020

Degree: BEng Chemical Engineering with Energy engineering (1st class with Honour)

During this course, I have experienced and learned about all basic chemical equipment, both in the laboratory and the industry. Group design projects are also done every year to stimulate and challenge our understanding of chemical engineering. It also allows me to strengthen my time management and teamwork skills. I am well versed in certain chemical engineering theories, such as particle technology and reaction engineering. I am experienced with a wide range of software including Fusion 360, MATLAB, Aspen HYSYS, Excel Visual Basic, Adobe Photoshop and Aspen Plus.

## Key projects and modules

# Applied Data Science (Data Science) Oct 2021 – TBA

In this module, I have accomplished data handing and data preparation and applied different forms of analytical techniques to my data and carefully interpreted the results. I used python as my main IDE to program solutions to analytical problems on the data sets. I also acquire the knowledge of legal, ethical and professional considerations on data usage (such as UK GDPR) and deliver a critical and informative report about it.

#### Machine Learning 1 (Data Science) Oct 2021 – Dec 2021

From this module, I was able to learn about the systematic knowledge of different machine learning approaches and demonstrated an understanding of their application in real-world problems. I have also been able to produce practical implementations of these machine learning approaches and evaluate their merits and limitations.

#### Process Design Project (Final year Chem Eng) Oct 2019 – Apr 2020

As a group, we have designed a novel process plant to produce sustainable jet fuel and heavy hydrocarbon using carbon dioxide as a feedstock. I designed the annular combustion chamber in the gas turbine and modelled the reaction process. It is further optimised through programs including Aspen HYSYS and Aspen+. I also performed a HAZOP and safety analysis to maximise the health and safety of the project. Problem-solving and time management are the most essential skills that I have learned from this project, and I was pleased that I obtain some experience of it.

#### Process intensification (Final year Chem Eng) Sep 2019 – Dec 2019

Our group project design is to improve the cooling in electric vehicle battery packs during rapid charging and discharging. I was involved in researching novel technologies, such as microchannel heat exchangers and thermoelectric cooling. I was also responsible for the manufacturing of microchannel heat exchangers and their fabrication techniques. From this group design project, I was very innovative and actively listened to different forms of ideas to improve the project further. I was able to gain some skills in team leadership and problem-solving skills.

## Work experiences and achievements

#### University of Bath Sept 2021 - Sept 2022

Academic Representative of MSc Data Science

- Support students and thoroughly communicate with the director of studies to report any events concerning the students
- · Conduct unbiased surveys and collect feedback about the module of the course
- Completed the training course for academic representatives

#### **Aircraft Career Development Association**

June 2021 - Sept 2021

Internship trainee

- Understand the principles of aircraft safety and the materials on different parts of the aircraft
- Thorough knowledge of the aircraft systems and their purpose
- Analysis and understanding of the weather reports for aircraft navigations

#### Bank of Taiwan SA Branch

Dec 2020 - April 2021

Intern

- Understanding the operations done in a commercial bank, especially in loan businesses including international syndication loans
- Knowledge of obtaining credit/loan facilities from commercial banks.
- A brief understanding of the analysis of financial statements, including income statements, balance sheets, etc.
- Completed the FAIS RE5 examination on the legislation of Financial Service Provider
- An adequate amount of knowledge on FAIS and FICA legislation implemented in all categories of FSP (Financial Service Provider)

## **Heriot-Watt University Edinburgh**

### Sept 2018 - Apr 2019

Student ambassador

- Rehearsing with a senior student ambassador and other student ambassadors to prepare for upcoming events.
- Organise and help guide the groups of newcomers and freshers
- Advertise the speciality of the university and give out advice to those who had trouble choosing their course in the
  university.
- Look out for suspicious items or personnel who do not belong in the university

## **Extracurricular activities and achievement**

- Troubleshooting PC hardware
- Cooking: Mainly vegetarian food and other meat alternative dishes
- Media creation, experienced in video editing programs e.g., Sony Vegas Pro, Windows Movie Maker
- Discovering and fixing my 125cc moped
- Listening to classic and vintage music of the 1900s.